Sachin Sharma

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

Location: Gaur City 2 Noida U.P India Email: sachinshoff@gmail.com | Mobile: 7017284451

SR. FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Experienced as Full Stack Blockchain developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Blockchain, React.js, Next.js, Express.js, Redux, Node.js, MongoDB, Solidity, Javascript, Typescript, jquery. Strong engineering professional with a MCA focused in Computer Science.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Backend & Frontend Development: Building scalable web applications.
- Agile Methodologies: Experienced in Scrum for efficient project delivery.
- API Development: Designing and integrating APIs.
- Blockchain Development: Building smart contracts on EVM and private blockchains.
- Cryptocurrency Integration: Developing wallets and integrating crypto transactions.
- NFTs & Token Standards: Creating NFTs with ERC-721, ERC-1155, and ERC-20.
- DApp Development: Building decentralized applications using Web3.js and ethers.js.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SCSS

Frameworks : React.js, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Express, Node.js, web3.js, ethers.js, GraphQL, Micro frontend

Libraries : Material UI, Redux, React Router, NPM Packages, Bootstrap, Tailwind

Databases : MongoDB, Redis

Databases : MongoDB, MySql, Redis

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Git, Gitlab, BitBucket, JIRA, Postman

DevOps : Nginx, Docker, CI/CD, Heroku, Netlify

: RabbitMQ, Web Sockets **Event Queues**

Blockchain : EVM Blockchains, NFT, Solidity, DApps, ERC-20, ERC-1155, ERC-721 Tokens

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer Mai Labs Pvt Ltd.

Oct 2022 - Present Noida

Software Developer

March 2021 - Oct 2022 Kellton Tech Solutions Pvt. Ltd. Gurugram

PROJECTS

Kalp Studio

React.js, Redux, Node.js, Git, Express.js, ethers.js, Micro-Frontend, EVM, NPM

- MicroFrontend development: Spearheaded the implementation of micro-frontend architecture, leading the project from inception
- Smart Contract Deployment: Enabled users to deploy their smart contracts using Self-Custodial, Custodial, and MPC wallets on EVM blockchains and Kalptantra private blockchain..
- User Authorization (KALP-KYC): Added KYC functionality for secure and compliant user access.
- Transaction Signing and Crypto Transfer: Allowed users to sign transactions and transfer cryptocurrency.
- Crypto Wallet Widget: Designed and developed a reusable wallet widget for seamless integration into multiple applications.
- Kalp UI library: Created an NPM package for common UI components, ensuring consistent UI across all micro-frontends.
- Kalp Boilerplate Creator: Created an NPM package that setup a new boilerplate with CLI commands.

NiftiQ

Next.js, Redux, Node.js, Git, Express.js, ethers.js, ERC-1155

- A **blockchain-based NFT Marketplace** for buying, selling, and trading non-fungible tokens (NFTs) representing unique digital assets and collectibles.
- Facilitated communication between technical and non-technical stakeholders, ensuring project progress transparency and addressing concerns.

Mylpr

React.js, Redux, Node.js, Git, Next.js, Express.js, Web3.js, ERC-20, ERC-721

- A revolutionary tool that acts as the initial step in securing your Intellectual Property Rights.
- Implemented Know Your Customer (KYC) functionality using SDKs like Sumsub and Authbridge to enhance user verification and security.
- Integrated multiple payment gateways including CCAvenue, Razorpay, and Stripe to facilitate secure transactions.

Sach Foundation React.js, Al models

• Built an AI based QnA model and CMS using React.js, Next.js, REST APIs, and GraphQL.

Payment SDK, Wallet SDK

NPM

- Developed an NPM package for Payment Aggregator and KYC Aggregator by consolidating multiple vendors into one
 unified platform.
- Streamlined KYC operations by integrating multiple vendors into one efficient solution.

HUMBL Marketplace

React.js, Typescript, Git

• Translate wireframes and designs into good quality code and enhance application performance.

EDUCATION

Shivalik College of Engineering

Dehradun

B.tech (Electronics and communication engineering)

Aug 2017 – Jun 2021